这面包圈硬得跟冰球有得一拼
This bagel's as hard as a hockey puck.
那就别吃
Then don't eat it.
以前可是有全套早餐
Used to be a full breakfast service.
他们想饿死我们
They're trying to starve us.
你在担心食物
You're worried about the food?
不  我担心的是食物背后的象征
No, I'm worried about what the food represents.
我今天要拍7场戏
I got seven scenes to shoot today
预算只有以前的一半
On half of what we used to spend.
经济不景气
We're going through a recession.
事情就是这么简单
It is what it is.
可是没人会把我们从危机中解救出来
But nobody's gonna bail us out.
到处都是免费下载  厕所里卖DVD碟
Free content everywhere, dvd sales in the toilet.
现在股票结算室里那些精打细算
Now the back office bean counters
之辈把我半数的主意都否定了
Are vetoing half my ideas.
所以现在专心到表演上来吧
So we begin to make it about the performances.
你能行吗
You okay?
头有点痛
A bit of a headache.
要是你需要止痛药
If you need an ibuprofen--
我要你把专业态度拿出来  行不
I need you to put your game face on, all right?
试着对付面包圈和布景和服装
Screw the bagels, screw the sets, screw the wardrobe.
你知不知道我们有多幸运
Do you have any idea how lucky we are?
能做自己喜欢做的事
We get to do something we like,
接触人们的生活  而且还能从中得到收入
We get to touch people's lives and we get paid for it?
来拍电影吧
Let's make a movie.
嗨  宝贝
Hey, baby.
摄像机到位
Roll camera.
然后
And...
开拍
Action.
有什么不对劲吗
What's wrong?
我的眼睛...
My eyes...
好像在爆炸一样
They feel like they're exploding.
好吧  把那该死的灯关上
All right, turn off the damn lights.
叫救护车  现在就去
Get an ambulance. Now!
我们要迟到了
We're gonna be late for work.
那就迟吧
Then we'll be late.
你夺走了一个病人的生命 你为此说谎说了几个星期
You took a patient's life, You lied about it for weeks,
你触犯了鬼知道多少条法律和契约
You broke who knows how many laws and oaths
来掩饰真相
To cover it up,
但我能容忍这些
But I can live with it.
我们能一起渡过去
We can get through it together.
你不知道我受了多少苦
You have no idea what I've been living with,
也不会知道你说的一切意味着什么
And what it means to hear you say that.
但我们得离开医院
But we need to get away from princeton-plainsboro.
你都不能走近迪巴拉接受治疗的房间
You can barely walk by the rooms where dibala was treated.
如果我们有换个新局面的机会
Why should we live with that hanging over our heads?
为什么我们还要让这个威胁我们呢
If there was ever a time to turn the page...
是高烧的三岁婴儿  不间断流涎
Three-month-old with fever, incessant drooling,
还有慢性肌肉无力
And chronic muscle weakness.
还是
Or...
色情影星汉克·哈德科  本名亨利·洛夫科斯基
Porn actor Hank Hardwick, born Henry Lefkowitz,
表面看起来没有任何疾病
Totally clean workup,
工作时因极度恐光症崩溃
Collapsed on the job with extreme photophobia.
还是...
Or...
一个虚弱得像破布娃娃的婴儿
An infant as limp as a rag doll.
好  等Chase和Cameron来吧
Yeah. Let's wait till chase and cameron get here.
我有预感  他们的判断力好得足以支持我
I have a feeling they'll have the good sense to side with me.
他们支持谁不重要  我还是管事的
Doesn't matter who they side with, I'm still in charge.
我们接那个虚弱的三月大的婴儿
We're taking the limp three-month-old.
哦  太好了
Oh, good.
你去呼叫专治柔弱的专家吧
You paged the limpness specialist.
这信封怎么如此奇异地 有着行医执照的形状呢
This envelope is oddly medical license-shaped.
恭喜
Congratulations.
豪斯重新主管部门了
House is back in charge.
我们要治那个三级片影星了
We get to treat a porn star.
恭喜
Congratulations.
对我们真是绝佳的时机啊
Perfect timing for us.
我们要退出团队了
We're leaving the team
还有医院  立即生效
And the hospital, effective immediately.
真突然啊
That's kind of sudden.
除非你们已经到处投简历好一阵子了
Unless you've been circulating your resumes for a while.
我们刚刚开始考虑新工作
We're just starting to think about new jobs,
还有我们想住的地方
Where we want to live.
还要搬家  真有趣
Moving too. Interesting.
你们确定吗
Are you sure about this?
是
Yes.
我们会想你们的
Uh... We'll miss you.
我们也会想你们所有人的
We'll miss all of you too.
我们要开始收拾东西了
We'll start clearing out our things.
做性病和毒素排查
Run an std panel and a tox screen.
用C反应蛋白排查炎症
Send a c-reactive protein to look for inflammation
还有用抗核抗体排查自体免疫病
And an A.N.A. to screen for autoimmune.
剩下的去找病史
The rest of you take a history
然后做个腰穿来排除病毒性脑炎
And do an l.P. To rule out viral encephalitis.
对了  只有你一个
Oh, it's just you.
希望你善于多线程操作
Here's hoping you're good at multitasking.
我定期检查性病 我每个同事都是
I get tested for stds regularly, so does everyone I work with.
因为我猜你不信他们
Since I'm guessing you don't take their word for it.
好吧  我要你侧躺着
All right, I'm gonna need you to lie on your side
把膝盖拉到胸前
And put your knees to your chest.
有酗酒或滥用药物的历史吗
Any history of alcohol or substance abuse?
我妻子过去有吸一点药
My wife used to smoke a little pot,
但我没碰过那东西
But I never touched the stuff.
你结婚了
You're married.
很快乐  已经两年了
Happily, for two years now.
你拍色情片她高兴吗
She happy you do porn?
很高兴  因为她也拍
Very, since she does it too.
你妻子工作的时候你不吃醋吗
You ever get jealous when your wife's working?
那是工作
It's a job.
一旦你开始让你的职业生活 限制了你的生活
Once you start letting your work life rule your home life,
如果生活同样限制了你的工作
Especially if you're in the same line of work,
爱情就不会长久
Your relationship's gonna be short.
会有点压迫感
You're gonna feel a little pressure.
受到过性虐待吗
Any history of sexual abuse?
这么土的问题
I defy the cliche.
有没有觉得抑郁或者精神欠佳呢
Have you ever suffered depression or psychosis?
直接告诉你吧
Let me save you some time.
我的医药记录很干净
There's not a blotch on my medical record.
我认识这个圈子里的很多人
I know most of the people in my field
不是嗑药就是有恋父情结
are drug addicts with daddy issues,
可我来自郊区的犹太好小伙
But I'm a nice, Jewish boy from the 'burbs.
不是受生活所迫
I wasn't driven to this.
我选择这工作  我就相信
I chose it. I believe in it.
我真的觉得...
I actually think it's--oh!
我的胳膊很疼
My arms are killing me.
好像是强直痉挛  你的肌肉在收缩
Looks like tetany. Your muscles are contracting.
在这里注射哌替啶
Need some meperidine in here.
天哪
Oh, god.
犹太人  大老二  恐光症  肌肉痉挛
Jew with megalophallus, photophobia, and muscle spasm.
你来说哪个症状最不寻常
You tell me which is the most unusual.
四个候选人  三个空缺
Four candidates, three slots on the team.
我得看看你是不是还有能力诊断
Need to know if you've still got your diagnostic chops.
我每天六点离开办公室
I leave this office by 6 every day
我又开始过周末
I have my weekends again,
重新了解我的妻子
I recognize my wife again.
明白了  真没劲
Yeah, I agree. Does sound pretty dull.
难怪你想为我工作
No wonder you want to work for me.
毒理检查正常
Tox screen was clean,
排除了病毒性脑炎
We ruled out viral encephalitis.
你回来的唯一障碍是你妻子
The only obstacle to you coming back is your wife.
她从来没有让你这么为难过
Which has never been that much of an obstacle to you.
也许你是对的
Maybe you're right.
眼睛和肌肉的唯一联系是大脑
The only link between eye and muscle is the brain.
肿瘤  癫痫
Tumor, seizure...
陶博觉得是大脑的问题
Taub seems to think the link has to be the brain,
可是眼睛和肌肉取决于病人大脑
But eye and muscle are governed by different parts
的不同部位
of the patient's second-favorite organ.
这就是说
Which means it's...
泰国很不错  谢谢关心
Thailand was wonderful. Thanks for asking.
当然  也可能是多病灶
Of course. Yes. It has to be multifocal.
我两小时后
I have an interview
跟社区健康诊所有个面试
With a community health clinic in two hours.
备用计划不错
Back-up plan's fine.
陶博全垒打获胜
Taub's swinging for the fences.
我建议你别分心
I suggest you don't divide your attention.
说的对
Good point.
那我不会分心
I won't divide my attention, then.
陶博觉得是大脑的问题
Taub thinks it's a brain issue,
13号觉得是多病灶
Thirteen thinks it's multifocal.
而且他们都不想在这工作
And neither of them wants to work here.
别听他们说瞎说
Don't take their word for it.
陶博的问题是他老婆  13号的问题是你
Taub's problem is his wife, thirteen's problem is you.
奇斯和卡梅隆的问题是那个死了的非洲独裁者
Chase and Cameron's problem is the dead African dictator.
没有一个人是工作有问题
None of them has a problem with the work.
脑血管炎能很好的解释
Cerebral vasculitis would explain
眼睛和胳膊的临床症状
Both the eye and arm findings.
用类固醇  做大脑血管造影确认
Steroids to treat, brain angiogram to confirm,
顺便再做肌电图和神经活组织检查
Emg and nerve biopsy while you're at it.
我要吃午饭
I'll be at lunch.
我要聘四个人
I'd hire all four,
可是五个人的小组太笨重了
But a five-person team seems unwieldy.
你打算拒绝谁
Who would you turn down?
跟他要一样的
I'll have whatever he's buying.
两个芝士汉堡包  两个大份薯条
Two cheeseburgers and two large fries.
世界上有那么多人
There are a thousand people in the world
想为你工作
Who want to be on your staff,
可是你盯着四个不想做的
But you're going after the four who don't.
他们不愿意是因为他们的生活
They don't because their lives
那么无关紧要而且烦人地复杂
are irrelevantly and annoyingly complicated,
让他们困惑
Which makes them confused,
让他们做出不妥的决定
Which makes them make poor decisions.
你的生活很简单吗
And your life is simple?
你竭尽全力去医学会议
You went all the way up to the medical conference
为了奉承卡迪
To cozy up to cuddy.
而她却在跟这世界上
Instead she's dating one of two people in the world
你仅有的两个朋友之一约会
you think of as a friend.
不可能你不受伤
There's no way that's not devastating.
我还是有点魅力的
So I had an attraction of sorts.
在你想象的约会里
Yeah, the sort in which your imaginary tryst
把你送去精神病院
Landed you in a mental hospital.
我得到了帮助
And I got help.
她有了卢卡斯  还给我买了姜汁汽水
And she got lucas, who bought me a ginger ale.
这挺好的
It's all fine.
在我的部门里却不可能实现
Which won't be true of my department
除非想出来我不打算雇谁
Unless I can figure out which doctor I'm not hiring.
我想让你自己回来工作
I suppose throwing yourself into your work
不是最糟的事
isn't the worst thing you could do.
最糟的是什么
What is the worst thing I could do?
豪斯觉得是心血管炎
House thinks it's cerebral vasculitis.
如果你能帮我做脑部血管造影
If you could just do the brain angio
我就可以完成血液检测了
While I finish up the blood work--
我们不干了
We're out the door.
他让我自己做所有的测试和治疗
He's got me running every test and treatment by myself.
这就是你为什么也会被踢掉
Which is why you should be out the door too.
就算是豪斯  这也是无理取闹
This is completely unreasonable, even for house.
这是你欠我的
You owe me this.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你真的相信这是脑血管炎吗
You really believe this is cerebral vasculitis?
可能是
Could be.
豪斯打算往他的脑子里放根导管
House wants to thread a catheter through his brain,
这可能导致血管痉挛
Which could cause a vasospasm,
用类固醇
Give steroids,
这可能导致全身感染
Which could spread infection all over the place,
因为有这个可能
Because it could be.
像豪斯的作风
Sounds like house.
也有可能是维生素D缺乏症
It could also be a severe vitamin d deficiency.
他的饮食受到限制而且长期在室内工作
He's a restrictived diet and works long hours indoors,
因此低血钙  抽搐  恐光
Became hypocalcemic, got tetany and photophobia.
你是说我不该做血管造影吗
Are you saying I shouldn't do the angio?
这是豪斯的命令  福曼也这样要求
House ordered it, Foreman wants it,
我们当然得做
Of course we should do it.
我只是想说明我们离开是对的
I'm just saying we're right to leave.
是吗
You sure?
因为现在我基本上对你唯命是从
Because right now I'll basically do anything you ask me.
我才没兴趣揭你的伤疤让你内疚
I'm not interested in guilting you.
我们得开始新的生活
We're moving on.
等我把病人带到光疗套房
Right after I take the patient to the phototherapy suite,
照紫外线
Blast him in ultraviolet light,
然后再注射点他极度缺乏的维生素D
And I.V. vitamins for his severe vitamin d deficiency.
你们在一起工作吗
So do you guys actually work together?
起初是
We did at first,
但现在我们分开拍摄
But now we like to keep our films produced separate.
那你会看她工作吗
So do you, uh, watch her work?
我们都有自己的事情要忙
We're both busy with our own stuff.
随便你们怎么想吧
Think what you want,
我们对自己的工作很自豪
But we're proud of what we do.
把性和感情分开
Divorcing sex from all emotional content?
感情是情绪上的  性是生理的
Emotion is emotional. Sex is mechanical.
它们之间不需要有交集
There doesn't really need to be any overlap.
当然了  对你们来说的话
Certainly not in your world.
通过把性从一些根深蒂固的传统思想中
We've helped a lot of couples
脱离出来  我们帮助了很多夫妻
By taking sex out of some deep, dark dungeon.
做任何你想做的事
Do what you want
而且没有道德报应
Without some big, moral comeuppance.
你以为你可以逃避后果  但事实上不能
You think you can escape the consequences, but you can't.
你没有建立自己的原则或道德准则
You don't get to make your own rules or morals.
你只负责治疗他
Well, you're here to treat him,
不需要指点我们的  汉克
Not lecture us about our--Hank.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
-你没事儿吧  -只是流鼻血而已
- Are you okay?  - Just a nosebleed.
看他腿上
Inside his leg?
点状出血
Petechial hemorrhages.
我们错了  福曼也是
We were wrong. So was Foreman.
病人的血不凝结
Patient's blood won't clot.
我们又回到原点了
We're back to square one.
你又回到我的办公室了
And you're back in my office.
毕竟是很难得到的工作  不舍得放弃
So much for playing hard to get.
我们只是来帮福曼的
We're just here to help Foreman.
那不是
Is that--
他并非没有才
He's not without talent.
紫外线使他的毛细血管更脆弱
UV rays made the patient's capillaries more fragile,
从而加速了血管内凝血
Hastening the onset of D.I.C.
听起来像败血症
Sounds like sepsis--
不是  没有休克症状
But isn't. No sign of shock.
-血压没降低  -能把那个关掉吗
- No drop in blood pressure. - Can we turn that off?
是啊  因为卡梅隆认为看黄片不道德
Right, 'cause Cameron thinks pornography is evil.
我不介意他做了什么 也不在乎你在看什么
I don't care what he does. I don't care what you watch.
只是他假装这是一种我们都该渴望的
I just think it's annoying that he pretends
美好生活  这一点让我很厌烦
It's some beautiful life we should all be aspiring to.
回到菌血症上来
Let's shift points to bacteremia.
没有发热
No fever.
也无法解释痉挛性肌肉收缩
Plus it wouldn't explain his spasmodic muscle contractions.
这点阻碍就让你们退缩啦
The ball and chain smacked you down.
但大面积的点状皮疹
But widespread petechial rash,
关联到神经系统
Nervous system involvement.
像是某种血液感染
It's some kind of blood infection.
脑膜炎球菌血症
Meningococcemia.
给他注射肝素缓解血管内凝血
Start the patient on heparin for the D.I.C.
打广谱抗生素来治疗脑膜炎球菌血症
Broad-spectrum antibiotics for the meningococcemia.
卡梅隆医生
Dr. Cameron.
奇斯又轻松自在  和你步调一致了
Chase is relaxed, at ease, in lockstep with you again.
我猜他终于告诉你他杀死了小阿迪伊明
I guess he finally told you that he iced Idi Amin jr.
那是否也意味着他可以打破
Does that mean he can break
另外九条戒律呢[十戒]
The other nine commandments too?
忽视上帝的存在的话  当然了
Taking the lord's name in vain, sure,
垂涎邻居的妻子
But coveting thy neighbor's wife?
她性感吗
Is she hot?
我已经原谅他了
I've forgiven him.
不是因为谋杀  不该你原谅
Not for murder. Not you.
不管迪巴拉有多邪恶
Doesn't matter how evil Dibala was.
但每一次良心的问候
By every conscience-hugging,
德雷莎修女的慈爱在你身体里交织时
Mother teresa-loving bone in your body,
你应该离开他  而不是和他在一起
You should be leaving him, not living with him.
我以为你会认为我们的离开只是个诡计
I thought your position was our leaving is a ruse.
我们不是要讨论我的观点
We're not talking about my position,
我们在讨论你的  不合情理的做法
We're talking about yours, which doesn't add up.
这才真是不合情理
Here's what doesn't add up.
如果你真想为你的团队增加人员的话
If you were serious about staffing your team
你会很确切的知道你需要的是哪三个人
You would know exactly which three fellows you wanted.
你之前就已经想好了这件事
You plowed ahead with this case
尽管你还没有请到新人
Even though you hadn't hired new fellows
因为你知道福曼会找奇斯和我帮忙
Because you knew Foreman would ask Chase and me to help,
也让你有更多时间来破坏我们的婚姻
Giving you more time to blow up our marriage.
我可没想那样
I don't want that.
但如果不提前计划好的话就实在太蠢了
But we'd be foolish not to plan ahead.
首先  我炒了奇斯是两年前你离开的主要原因
A--my firing Chase was the only reason you left two years ago,
其次  当他杀过人的恐惧感侵袭你时
B--when the full horror of his homicide hits you,
你们的婚姻就完蛋了
Your marriage will blow up.
最后
And z...
阻止你在这里工作的唯一障碍消失了
The only obstacle to your working here will be gone.
或者我省略了一些话
Or maybe I skipped a couple of letters.
脑膜炎球菌血症具有传染性
Meningococcemia's spread person-to-person.
所以你应该考虑一下
Something you ought to think about
下次出演的时间
Next time you show up for work.
没关系了  你妻子不在这里
It's okay. Your wife's not here.
我在告诉你
I'm just telling you what--
当她在时你得装成正人君子  我明白
You have to lecture me when she's around, I get it.
但从你所问的问题中我可以看出来
But I can tell from all the questions you ask
其实你和我很像  只是不愿承认罢了
That you're more like me than you admit.
我是男人
I'm a guy.
我偶尔会乱来  但我爱我的妻子
I look around every once in a while, but I love my wife.
她是我唯一一个很亲密的人
I love the fact that she's the only one that I'm intimate with.
难道你就一点都不想
And no part of you wants to just
从别人强加于你的这些规则里面摆脱出来吗
Toss this rule book everyone's forced on you?
你就不想过有真实诺言的生活吗
No part of you wants a life of actual commitment?
我和我妻子的这种关系很完美吗  不
Is my relationship perfect? No.
当我妻子刚做了九个小时的爱之后
Am I ever horny when my wife has
我还会性激动吗
just had sex for nine hours?
会
Yes.
在所有重要事情上
But we are committed to each other,
我们对对方都很忠诚
In every way that matters.
换句话说  除了你不忠诚的时候
In other words you're committed,
你都是忠诚的
Except when you're not committed.
若你有良知的话  那套理论就不管用了
Doesn't work so well if you have a conscience.
良知
Conscience.
你指当没有合理的理由照人们所期望的
You mean that thing that kicks in when there's no logical reason
方式去做的时候  拿来安慰自己东西吗
to behave the way people want you to?
怎么回事
What?
你发烧了
You have a fever.
也就是说抗生素不管用
Means the antibiotics aren't working.
高山先生
Mr. Takayama.
在
Yes.
上次那个人对我眼睛的治疗让我很满意
I'm really happy with what the last guy did with my eyes.
但为什么广谱抗生素
But why would broad-spectrum antibiotics
对脑膜炎不起作用呢
Fail to work on meningococcemia?
请原谅  我还有真实的病人
If you'll excuse me, I've got a real patient.
希特勒先生
Mister... Hitler.
别闹了
Really.
在接待员忙着和她男朋友调情的时候
Had to do something to amuse myself while your receptionist
我得自娱自乐一下
Fought with her boyfriend.
下一个是谁
Who's next?
是这个需要吃二十年的玉米片
A guy who needs two decades' worth of corn chips
来减掉身上的肥肉的人
Hoovered out of his neck,
还是一个不能接受日光
Or a guy who can't stand daylight,
血液也不凝结的患者
And whose blood won't clot.
你来选择治疗谁
You do the triage.
这个混蛋是谁
Who's the jerk?
一个绝无可能重新雇用我得人
Someone with zero chance of hiring me back.
我告诉过你了
I told you.
我对我的家庭和工作都很满意
I'm content at home and at work.
但你不满足于就此满足
But you're not content with content.
所以你才陷入股票欺诈
That's why you got sucked into those stock scams,
欺骗你深爱的妻子
Why you cheated on the wife you love.
在打桥牌的时候
At bridge.
我妻子和我经常打桥牌
My wife and I play a lot of bridge.
为什么上次我来的时候你会诊断病例
Why you worked on a case last time I was here.
我告诉你了一个方法
I gave you a theory.
就像我帮餐馆里的人把堵在
Just like I'd help a guy who needs
喉咙里的异物弄出来一样
A heimlich in a restaurant.
然后我就让你走了
And then I shut the door behind you.
但恐怕你得击败其他三个医生才能给他治疗
But you'd knock over three other doctors to give it to him.
比喻的说法是  你对海姆利克有瘾
Metaphorically speaking, you're a heimlich addict.
而你是个瘾君子
And you're an addiction addict.
现在你唯一的毒品来源是你的老团队
Right now your drug of choice is your old team,
像其他瘾君子一样  你试图借此解决
And like any addict you're trying to solve
一些其他问题  但却不管用
Some other problem and it's not gonna work.
很抱歉  我有
If you'll excuse me, I have a--
你有繁忙的工作日程如鼻部手术
You have a tight schedule of nose jobs
整腹手术
And tummy tucks.
没错  我做鼻部手术
Yes. I do nose jobs.
比如车祸之后被送过来的那个人
Just like the guy who came here after a car crash,
甚至不能呼吸  用他的
Couldn't even breathe through his...
如果他的静脉窦被感染和阻塞了的话
Antibiotics wouldn't work if his sinuses
抗生素是不会有效的
Were infected and clogged.
如果有一团细菌阻挠
If there was a pocket of bacteria
他的血液就不能到达脑部
His blood vessels couldn't reach.
你通过外科手术清空静脉窦 药就会有用了
You surgically drain his sinuses the drugs will work.
好主意
Nice.
那样不好受吧
Tell me that didn't feel good.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
别再来了
Not coming back.
看来这次旅行很愉快
Looks like quite a trip.
是啊
It was.
豪斯让你来跟我谈的吗
House send you to talk to me?
不是
No.
那就没什么好谈的了
Then there's nothing to talk about.
我不想替他工作
I don't want to work for him.
你是个很棒的医生
You're a great doctor.
让你加入这个团队  豪斯是对的
House is right to want you in the mix.
这样说是因为你仍对我有好感
Are you saying this because you still have feelings for me
想让我回去吗
And you want me to come back?
我是说那不是问题
I'm saying that shouldn't be an issue.
你到底还喜不喜欢我
Do you have feelings for me or not?
我不希望我们在工作中
I don't want our work life
牵扯到任何私人感情
To have anything to do with our personal life.
你不能把这两件事分开
You couldn't keep them separate.
这也是为什么我们没有个人的生活空间
And that's why our personal life doesn't exist.
我们都没必要
None of that has to--
我不能跟你一起工作
I can't work with you.
事实上  你可以的
Actually, you can.
我才是有问题的那一个
I was the one who had the problem.
我再不会了
I don't anymore.
我欠你一个道歉
I owe you an apology.
我...错...
I was wr-rr-r...
我...错...了
I was wrr-r-rr...
你哪错了
What were you wrong about?
你花了几周时间去努力地隐藏一件事
You spent weeks elaborately concealing the fact that you...
你撞了你爸爸的车
Crashed daddy's car.
你却承认了
And then you just confessed.
听起来很白痴  必会以彻底的失败而告终
Seemed idiotic. Certain to end in disaster.
然而你们要一起驶向落日的余晖
Instead you're riding off into the sunset together.
有什么理由解释吗
Any theories on why?
我想你已经
I assume you've already
不再考虑"她爱我"这个原因了
Dismissed the "she loves me" theory?
哦  这有可能
Well, it's possible.
那需要预先假定
It would require the presupposition
她在过去六年里所做的每一件事
That everything she's done for the last six years
与她的性格完全不相符
Has been completely inconsistent with her character.
但是是的  这有可能
But yeah, it's possible.
正如我们已结婚
And as we've already established,
也有可能你是错的
It's also possible that you're wrong.
或者有另外一个解释
Or there's another explanation.
既然你没有什么解释  我会一直找你的
Since you don't have one, I'm gonna keep looking for you.
让液体排干净  然后塞上麻醉剂和消毒纱布
Let him drain, then pack it with anesthetics and sterile gauze.
你知道豪斯在干嘛吗
Do you have any idea what's going on with House?
他正努力把那些老伙伴弄回来
Uh, he's trying to get his old fellows back?
这叫做跟踪
It's called stalking.
我正忙着应付法院人员
I am way too busy to play officer of the court.
太可惜了  你可是整件事的起因
That's a shame, since you're the one who triggered this.
对了  你怎么看卢卡斯
What do you see in Lucas anyway?
我不觉得这跟你有什么关系
I don't see that it's any of your business.
你觉得豪斯不会发现吗
Did you think House wouldn't find out?
你至少可以事先告诉我  我就不用教他
You could've at least told me so I wouldn't have coached him
怎样证明自己对你的重要性
On how to prove his worthiness to you.
我知道你对我失望了
I know you're upset with me
因为我没有选择跟你最好的朋友约会
Because I didn't choose to date your best friend.
但是我在过我的生活
But I'm living my life.
也是第一次我不用仅仅因为
And for the first time I'm not gonna change that.
这可能会影响他或者你而改变
Because of how it might affect him or you.
真是烦死我了
I feel like crap.
是的  我们的关系是跟豪斯有关
Yeah, look, our relationship is gonna be about House,
还是跟我们自己有关
Or it's gonna be about us.
我觉得该跟我们自己有关
I vote for it being about us.
豪斯会替我们选择跟他有关
Well, House is gonna make it about him for us.
这很让人不舒服
This is very insulting.
你明显被这个影响了
You're apparently shocked by this,
就是说你觉得我们应该
Which means that you thought that there
有一些什么方式约个会
Was some way that we could date,
结个婚  生两个孩子  再养个狗
Get married, have two kids, a dog,
退休去佛罗里达  所有这些都不让豪斯知道
Retire to Florida, all without House finding out.
还是  你觉得我们约不约会无所谓
Or you thought that we wouldn't date all that long.
第一种可能意味着你在妄想
First means you're delusional.
第二种意味我在妄想
The second means I'm delusional.
严格地说这也可能是说
Technically it could also mean
你觉得豪斯是个成熟的男人
You thought House had matured,
但是我们仍然会回到现实
But then we're back to your being--
闭嘴
Shut up.
你是对的  对不起
You're right. I'm sorry.
过奖了
I'm also flattered.
是的  因为你和威尔森一起做了许多的事
Yeah, 'cause you acted all cool and everything with wilson,
但你跟我在一起会感觉很舒服 你可以随时对我发脾气的
But you feel comfortable enough with me that you can freak out.
很爽吧
That's cool.
他的鼻窦清理干净了
His sinuses are clear.
抗生素这回能起作用了
Antibiotics should work this time.
你为什么会原谅我
Why did you forgive me?
我是说  我  我很高兴
I mean, I'm--I'm glad.
我很感激  但是我也很困惑
I'm grateful, but I'm confused.
你对病人要比对我严格得多
You've been harder on the patient than you've been on me.
你和病人的区别是
Well, the difference between you and the patient
你会感到羞耻
Is that you feel shame.
内疚
Guilt.
这也是我为什么知道我们会渡过这个难关
That's how I know we're gonna get through this.
我的胃
My stomach.
很疼
It really hurts.
他的肝脏衰竭
His liver's failing.
His liver's failing and
下腹一直在积水  所以
His abdomen Keeps filling with fluid, so--
他得的不是脑膜炎
It's not meningococcemia.
不管你们多想结束对方的话
No matter how much you finish each other's sentences,
都指望以此做一个打包的诊断
Don't count on being a diagnostic package deal.
病人的肝脏有毛病了
Patient's liver's not working.
我们没时间在这猜来猜去了
We don't have time for your little team-stakes.
有时候你...也是...错的
Sometimes you're just wr-rr-r-wrong.
遗传基因
Something genetic,
还有他的家族病史我们忽略的吗
Something in his family history we overlooked?
家族病史和遗传基因都没问题
History and genetics are spotless.
只是他小时候咳嗽得很厉害的时候
Plus every time he had a bad cough as a kid
会去看医生
He went to a doctor.
是胆管囊肿阻塞了胆汁腺吗
Klatskin tumor obstructing his bile ducts?
没有黄疸症状  那不会影响到眼睛
No jaundice. Wouldn't have ocular effects.
但如果是胆管内发炎
But if it's inflammation inside the bile channels,
硬化性胆管炎
Sclerosing cholangitis.
会让他不再产生
Could've stopped him from producing
血凝蛋白质  破坏他的血细胞
Clotting proteins, damaged his blood cells,
-引起一系列连锁反应  -够了
- Causing small strokes. - Enough!
够了
Enough!
别再打击13和陶了
Stop pummeling thirteen and Taub.
很吻合
It fits.
准备给病人进行内镜逆行胰腺插管术
Prep the patient for an ERCP.
看有没有希望打通
See if there's any hope of opening
他阻塞的胆汁通道
His blocked bile channels.
再告诉他开始找肝脏捐赠者
And tell him to start looking for a liver donor.
奇斯医生
Dr. Chase.
轮到你了
Your turn.
她说了什么
So what'd she say?
她原谅我是因为我感到了愧疚
She forgave me because I feel guilty.
这也管用
That works too.
现在你希望我问你"也"指的是什么
And now you expect me to ask you what the "too" refers to.
只要你感兴趣
Only if you're interested.
只要你怀疑她的答案
Only if you have doubts about her answer.
她觉得你根本不用 为那件事情内疚
She thinks that you don't have anything to feel guilty about,
因为你没有杀死别人
Because you didn't kill anybody.
是我杀的
I did.
她责怪我是迪巴拉谋杀案的罪魁祸首 而不是你
She blames me for Dibala's murder, Not you.
你只是稍稍涉及了那个医疗案  她知道的
You were barely involved in that case. She knows that.
但是我创造了大的  坏的  邪恶的环境
But I created the big, bad, evil climate
导致了它的发生
That allowed it to happen.
你错了
You're wrong.
强势的辩论
Powerful counter-argument.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
你为什么想让事情变得无法收拾
Why are you trying to screw things up?
你把时态搞错了
You got the tense wrong.
事情已经不可收拾了
Things are already screwed up.
所以你不能只是希望为我工作
Which is why you don't just want to work for me,
你必须这么做
You need to.
卡梅隆觉得你不过是我的私人手偶
Cameron thinks you're my personal sock puppet.
如果你不留下来  就很难证实你不是
If you don't stay, it's gonna be hard to prove you're not.
我得走了
I have to go.
上周  我的手杖只能坚持十分钟
Last week, my cane could only do ten minutes.
你来这干什么
What are you doing here?
等你偷个懒这样我能跑在前面
Waiting for you to take a nap so I can surge into the lead.
让患有硬化性胆管炎的病人
What's the best way to restore the liver in someone
恢复肝脏的最好方式是什么
With sclerosing cholangitis?
不想被卷进去
Not getting drawn into this.
你已经在其中了
You already are.
因为你毁了我的训练吗
Because you crashed my workout?
你在进行核心训练
You're doing core training.
这样能提高平衡性
Which improves balance,
还能延迟亨廷顿疾病所带来的
Which staves off the most debilitating
身体最虚弱的症状
Symptoms of huntington's.
你已经度过了自我放逐的阶段
You've ended your self-destructive streak.
现在想做一些有用的事情
Want to do something significant,
一些比你所剩不多的几年
Something that'll last longer
持续更久的事情
Than the few years you have left.
我的团队是你的第一选择
My team is your first-best choice.
我的第一选择是加入昨天我面试的
My first choice is the community health clinic
社区健康诊所
I interviewed with yesterday.
当然了  你应该做那个
Absolutely, you should do that.
一周三个小时  每个医生都该选择它
Three hours a week. Every doctor should.
因为每个医生都能应付
'cause every doctor can.
但是你不想做普通医生
But you don't want to be every doctor.
另外  加入我的团队的话
Plus, on my team,
你可以和福曼周旋
You get to screw with Foreman.
无处不在  但仅字面理解范围
Every way but literally.
你为什么要用这种方法
Why are you doing it this way?
你假装我们都会回去
You're pretending to assume we're all coming back
却连问都不问我们一下
Without actually asking us.
为什么
Why?
这就是你为什么会痛苦地
See, this is why you'd be miserable
在诊所哭鼻子
Wiping noses in a clinic.
你不问的原因是你怕被拒绝
You can't ask because you can't face the rejection.
为什么不呢  发生什么事情了
Why not? What's going on?
你在让我问你吗
Are you asking me to ask you?
我觉得你不该问  为了你  也为了我好
I'm saying you shouldn't, for your sake as well as mine.
我们不知道硬性化胆炎
We don't know how much the sclerosing cholangitis
对你的肝脏造成了多大伤害
Has damaged your liver.
可能是一年  可能有十年
It might be in a year, it might be in ten.
但是有很大可能你需要一个新的肝脏
But the odds are you're gonna need a new one.
你需要明白
And you should know,
虽然移植委员不会直说
While no transplant committee will say this openly,
但他们绝不会同意把器官
They'll never grant an organ
给做你这一行的人
To someone working in your profession.
你的意思是我得换工作
You're saying I have to change jobs?
你从医学角度建议我换工作
You're medically advising me to change jobs.
汉克  如果你太虚弱
Hank, if you're too sick--
她希望我改变宗教信仰
She wants me to have some kind of religious conversion.
事实上就是在唾弃它
She's practically salivating over it.
我只是直言相告关于
I'm just being candid about--
那你觉得我不贱
So you don't think I'm scum.
只是一些委员会成员觉得我贱
Just some committee thinks I'm scum.
你的生活方式有危险
That your lifestyle has risks.
你的工作比我能接触到更多 有病的人  细菌和血液
You work around more sick people and germs and blood than I do.
我才不会像我父母一样
I'm not gonna live my life afraid
畏惧我的生存方式
Like my parents did.
他们几乎都不让我出门
Barely letting me play outside
生怕我被抓伤
And god forbid that I get a scratch.
我跟他谈吧
I'll talk to him.
他会平静下来  意识到这是唯一
He'll calm down and realize that this is the only--
为什么每个人都想命令我怎么生活
Why does everyone want to dictate the way I live my life?
因为我们现在的生活方式会要了你的命
Because the way we're living is gonna kill you.
把胰管递给我
Passing the pancreatic duct...
不要听豪斯的
Don't listen to House.
你又不知道他说了什么
You have no idea what he said.
我知道豪斯很喜欢操纵人心
I know that House is manipulative.
我知道你现在处于脆弱期
I know that you're in a vulnerable state right now,
我知道卡梅隆希望你们的婚姻能顺利
And I know that Cameron wants your marriage to work.
你也是
So do you.
所以不要听豪斯的
So don't listen to House.
豪斯没有左右我的决定
House doesn't make my decisions.
现在是总胆管
We're in the common bile duct.
这些乱七八糟是什么  胆结石?
What's that mass? Gallstone?
可以放大五倍吗
Can we magnify times five?
那不是胆结石
That's not a gall stone.
他的肝脏里全是寄生虫
His liver's completely filled with worms.
你有杆线虫  是线虫的一种
You have strongyloides, also known as threadworms.
已经遍布全身了
They disseminated all over your body,
导致了你现在的所有症状
Causing all your symptoms.
我怎么会有寄生虫呢
How'd I get a parasite?
貌似是通过性传播的  但我们还不确定
Most likely through sexual activity, but we can't be sure.
该如何治疗
What's the treatment?
两片甲苯咪唑驱虫药
Two mebendazole pills.
就这么简单?
That's it?
你会好起来的  你的肝脏也是
You'll be fine. Your liver too.
回归你的生活去吧
Go back to your lives.
你知道这是医生休息室
You know this is the doctor's lounge.
我知道
I know.
貌似是读取医生报告的地方
It seemed like the place to read doctors' notes.
你很擅长嘛  顺便说一句
You are good at it, by the way.
你干吗看我的病历
Why are you reading my charts?
因为我担心我女友
Because I'm worried about my girlfriend.
你女朋友...
Your girlfriend...
是三级片男优吗
Is a male porn star?
不  我对象是丽萨·卡迪
Oh, no, I'm dating lisa cuddy.
真的吗
Seriously?
够酷吧
Cool, huh?
而且如果豪斯的团队解散了
And if house doesn't have his team,
她会很痛苦的  也会让我很痛苦
That'll make her miserable, which will make me miserable.
所以事实上
Which brings us to the fact that
你的作用至关重要
You have elevated noting to an art form.
我明白了
I see the connection.
大部分医生都写"上午九点"
Most doctors write "9:00 A.M."
只要时间差不多就好
If they scrub in or anything near it.
而你写九点零三分
you write 9:03
而且稍有延迟你就会做上小标记
And you make little notations when procedures are delayed.
你很敏感啊
You're easily impressed.
是啊  没错
Well, yeah.
曾经是  直到我看到你 在差不多四周前停止
I was, till I saw that you had virtually stopped writing them
写病历
About four weeks ago.
忙得很  就积压下了
Been busy. Got a backlog.
是吗
Yeah...
你这个水平的医生
People with your level of precision
应该不只是"积压"这么简单吧
Don't really just "get" backlogs.
没人知道你为什么要离开医院
No one knows why you're leaving ppth.
因为这是私人问题
Because it's personal.
如果发生了什么事的话
Well, if something happened,
我是说  如果你
I mean, if you're leaving
想逃避一些你曾经做过的事儿
To get away from something that you did,
或是她的  或是你们俩的
Or she did, or both of you did.
我的意思是  感情上也许你是想逃避
I mean, emotionally maybe you want to run away,
但以我的经验来看
But in my experience,
如果你被别人家院子里的恶狗盯上了
If you're staring at a pit bull in some guy's back yard,
你最好待在那别动
You're better off staying right where you are.
直面问题
Face the problem.
这样它才不会扑上来咬你屁股
That way it can't bite you in the ass.
谢谢你的寓言智慧
Thanks for the folksy wisdom.
你有其他三个人的把柄吗
Hey, you got any, uh, dirt on any of the other three?
这样会帮助我的
It'd really help me out.
我记得你说过他吃了那两片药就会好
I thought you said those two pills was all he needed!
肺部充满液体
Lungs are filling with fluid.
给他用气泵  输氧
Suction him and get him on oxygen.
病人肺部严重损坏
Patient's lungs are severely compromised.
肝功能仍在衰竭
Liver's still failing.
寄生虫可能是巧合
Worms could easily have been a coincidence.
他甚至惊奇怎么会有寄生虫
Almost be surprising if he didn't have 'em.
意味着可能是血液病
Which means it could be a hematological problem
外加心肌梗塞
Plus cardiomyopathy.
不  颈静脉平滑  心前区检查正常
No, neck veins are flat, precordial exam was normal.
可能是淋巴瘤吗
What if it's lymphoma?
腹腔癌症广泛侵犯会导致肝功能衰竭
Peritoneal carcinomatosis explains the liver failure.
肿瘤伴随综合症可以解释所有症状
Paraneoplastic syndrome explains everything else.
是淋巴瘤
Lymphoma it is.
准备给他做化疗
Prep him for chemo.
给陶博和13传真去最新情况
Fax taub and thirteen the latest update on the case.
真的吗
Seriously?
他们和团队里每个人一样有知情权
They have as much right to know as anyone on the team.
你到底是喜不喜欢诊断
You either like the diagnosis or you don't.
如果不喜欢  就继续说下去
If you don't, we need to keep talking.
如果喜欢  就闭嘴
If you do, you need to shut up.
我们没劲和你玩这愚蠢游戏了
What we don't need is this stupid game.
你冲豪斯发火  但你没冲我发火
You're mad at house, but you're not mad at me.
你想让我冲你发火吗
Do you want me to be mad at you?
你骂豪斯了  没骂我
You blame House. Not me.
我冲豪斯发火是因为他是个混蛋
I am mad at House because he's an ass.
我也想冲你发火  但我不想离开你
And I am mad at you, but I don't want to leave you.
我做了有生以来最糟糕的事情
What I did may be the worst thing I ever did.
也可能是最好的
It may be the best.
我既是个杀人犯  也是个阻止谋杀的角色
I'm either a murderer or a guy who stopped a mass murderer,
但确实是我做了  是我
But I did it. Me.
而且就算是曾经让我崩溃  但我今天仍要做
And even if it destroys me, I'd do it again today.
你不是这个意思  不像你
You don't mean that. This isn't you.
我不想逃避自己所做的一切
I'm not running away from what I did
只因为你想让我装作从未做过
Because you want to pretend I never did it.
如果你是那么想的...
If that's how you feel...
好吧
Okay.
我的策略毫不起作用
My strategy's not completely working.
他们四个都想跟我
All four of them want to work for me,
但他们四个也都有各自
But all four of them have reasons
不想跟我的理由
Why they don't want to work for me.
我怎么能选一个出来
How do I get them to take one from column a
其他都放弃呢
And none from column b?
对了
Right.
就这样  啥也不说
Right, by not saying anything,
你是说我已经有答案了
You're saying that the answer is inside me.
答案和问题没有任何关系
The answer has nothing to do with the question.
那么理论上说不算答案
Then it's not technically the answer.
你为什么需要这3个医生呢
Why do you need three of these doctors?
因为我知道他们很好
Because I know they're good.
其他医生归类到可能不错的类别
Other doctors fall into the "might be good" category.
这跟他们好不好没有关系
It has nothing to do with them being good.
你觉得他们大部分时间都是笨蛋
You think they're idiots half the time,
但他们让你觉得舒服
But they're comfortable.
你感觉被卡迪抛弃了
You feel abandoned by Cuddy,
所以靠接近你认识的人来安慰自己
So you're reaching out to people you know for comfort.
你说的没错
Oh, my god, you're right.
我根本不需要医生
I don't need doctors at all.
我需要的是一个好朋友
I just need a good friend.
卡迪说的没错
Cuddy's right.
也许  只是也许
Maybe, just maybe,
如果我不合作  你会意识到
If I don't play along, you'll realize
肤浅的方法不能解决深奥的问题
You can't solve a deeper problem with a surface solution.
如果你什么都不说问题会更深奥的
Would've been more profound if you hadn't said anything.
你没事吧
You okay?
正在解决
Getting through it.
要是你们两个不在这儿问题会简单很多
Be a lot easier once you two are away from here.
他在尿血
He's peeing blood.
血压升高
BPs rising.
心率250
Heart rate's up to 250.
心跳要停止了
He's going into cardiac arrest.
充电
Charging.
准备
Clear.
在出血
He's bleeding out.
他身体完全没反应
His body's completely giving out.
充电  准备
Charging. Clear.
他已经稳定了
We've got him stabilized,
但是没有红血球  白血球
But no red cells, no white cells,
血小板也几乎没有
Practically no platelets either.
甲苯咪唑会导致不良反应 但和他症状不同
Mebendazole can cause adverse effects, but nothing like this.
他昨天就已经不做电磁波了
He's been off EM since yesterday, anyway.
试着猜想任何可能性
Long passes, wild guesses, anything.
垂体机能减退
Hypopituitarism.
可能导致多器官衰竭
Could cause multi-organ failure if...
如果他的甲状腺激素不完全正常
If his thyroid hormone wasn't completely normal.
肾细胞癌
Renal cell carcinoma.
肾脏超声波没有问题
Renal ultrasound was clean.
我觉得是白血病
I'd say aleukemic leukemia.
骨髓没有制造足够的正常细胞
Marrow's not making enough normal cells...
烧蚀病人的骨髓
Ablate the patient's bone marrow.
找匹配的捐赠人
Find him a donor match.
你想烧蚀骨髓吗
You want to nuke the patient's marrow?
没有证据显示他贫血
He had no evidence of being anemic
或免疫缺陷
Or immune-compromised when he was admitted.
白细胞也正常
Perfect white count as well.
烧蚀可能会致死
Ablation could kill him
或者让他对传染病丧失抵抗力
Or leave him defenseless against an infection that could.
那就提出更好的建议
Well, then come up with something better.
正常治疗他也可能会死
He may as well die while we're treating him.
我找其他候选人参与进来
Okay with you if I bring the other candidates
你们没有意见吧
Into the loop now?
风险是及其微小的
The risks are, uh, they're really minimal.
我们会进行一系列无痛注射然后
We'll do a series of painless injections, and...
不好意思
Excuse me.
就像治疗普通门诊病人一样
The whole thing can be done as an outpatient.
你早上11点就走了吗
You were leaving at 11:00 A.M.?
相信我  马上就要结束了
Trust me, case is almost over.
福曼告诉我你打算烧蚀病人的骨髓
Foreman told me you're ablating the patient's marrow,
根据他自己放弃的没有依据的推测
On a non-theory that Foreman himself withdrew.
你会害死病人的
You're gonna kill the patient.
是因为我和卢卡斯的关系吗
Is this about me and Lucas?
我需要备选治疗方案
I want alternatives for the patient.
我也想
So do I.
我想加入
I want to be on the team.
你觉得它能挽救你的婚姻吗
You think that's gonna save your marriage?
不知道
I don't know.
四个候选  三个空缺
Four candidates, three spots.
我面临难题啊
I got a tough decision ahead of me.
瑞米  我是西品萨肯市
Hi, Remy, this is Doctor Turner
自由门诊的特纳尔医生
From the Pennsauken Free Clinic.
我们想见你  你来决定吧
We all loved meeting you, and, well, the job's yours.
给我回电话  我们约个时间
Call me back. Let's pick a start date.
我希望看起来自然
I want it to look natural.
我的意思是要年轻很多  但要自然
I mean, much younger, but natural.
可以同时去掉鱼尾纹吗
Can you get rid of the crow's feet altogether?
还是留下比较好
Or is it better to leave a trace of them?
反正我看起来也没有老到有眼纹的地步吧
I don't look old enough to have them anyway, do I?
当然
Absolutely.
我看起来老吗
I do look old enough?
不  什么  不好意思
No. What? I'm sorry.
稍等一下
Hang on a second.
你怎么在这儿
Why are you here?
因为我觉得我们错了
Because I think we're wrong.
可能将会出错
Which means something's gonna go wrong.
或者没有
Or right.
我是高山
Takayama here.
是我和13  停止烧蚀
It's me and thirteen. Stop the ablation.
原因呢
Because?
因为线虫
Those threadworms.
为什么线虫刚消失几个小时
Why would his body have gone to hell
他的身体就不行了
Just hours after they were gone?
蠕虫不会伤害他
The worms weren't hurting him.
它们在帮助他  他患有肠外克隆氏症
They were helping him. He has extraintestinal crohn's.
因为生活在过于干净
He got it from being raised in a too clean,
和过分保护的环境他才患上这种病
Too overprotective of an environment.
这是卫生假说
It's the hygiene hypothesis.
为什么发达世界会有这么多自身免疫疾病
Why there's so much autoimmune disease in the developed world,
而发展中国家却没有
And almost none in the developing world.
那些寄生虫抑制了克隆氏病发作
The worms were keeping the crohn's in check,
同时指导他的免疫系统
Teaching his immune system
如何忍辱负重生存下来
What it should've learned from eating dirt growing up.
一旦杀光寄生虫  他也危在旦夕了
Once you killed them, it started killing him.
也就是说  他肮脏的生活本无大碍
So his life of filth wasn't the problem,
企图净化才会带来问题
Clean living was.
给他用甲泼尼龙
Let's start him on methylprednisolone.
还有寄生虫
And some helminths.
虫子
Worms.
挺不错的啊
Cool, huh?
最优秀的三只鸭子
Best out of three?
你是个坏孩子吗
Have you been a bad boy?
我想回到队伍里
I want to be on the team.
你老婆会很高兴的
Good news for your wife.
谢谢你的讽刺
Thanks for the sarcasm.
我改变生活轨迹  努力挤出时间陪她
I reorganized my life to spend more time with her,
不过显然  我没有想象中那么爱她
But apparently I don't love her as much as I thought.
或者说  你更爱她一些
Or you love her more.
这份工作带给你的刺激程度
This job gives you the thrill
不亚于搞婚外情
You used to find through philandering.
用量杯和MRI骗人
Better to cheat with a beaker and an mri
总好过和银发女病号乱搞
Than one of your platinum-blonde plastic surgery patients.
有消息我会通知你
I'll let you know.
我告诉豪斯  自己仍想为他工作
I told House I want to work for him again.
留下来吧
Stay on the team.
你总是比我专注得多
You were always more into it than I was,
更专注于诊断病情
More interested in diagnostics.
除非豪斯猜对了你急于离开的原因
Unless House was right about why you want out.
这下位置全满了
Four for four.
我曾经爱上过你
I was in love with you.
真是个白痴
I was an idiot.
尝试着追随你  努力理解你
Tried to be like you, tried to understand you
就因为相信自己能治愈你
Because I thought I could heal you.
你几乎杀了那个病人
You almost killed that patient.
如果几乎挽救了他的性命意味着
If almost not saving his life means--
你早就知道病因了
You knew the diagnosis a long time ago.
用另一个病人的生命诱骗老部下回来
You risked another patient's life to bait your old team.
另一个
Another one?
是你杀死了迪巴拉
You did kill Dibala.
你左右他人的生活  也教会我们这么做
By playing god and teaching us to do the same.
我教会你们如何独立思考
I taught you to think for yourselves.
在你眼中他们甚至算不上人
You don't even think of them as people.
只是供你解谜的小白鼠
They're just lab rats for your little puzzles.
你去为人性歌颂吧
As you celebrate their humanity,
我宁可专注于解谜和挽救他们的性命
I'd rather solve those little puzzles and save their lives.
动机固然很重要
Motives do matter.
但人死也不能重生
Lives can't come second.
病人还活着  这就够了
The patient is alive. That's what matters.
你不会满足的
Not to you.
你只想让陶博和13也参与到这个游戏里
All you care about is that Taub and Thirteen fell for your game.
像毒害奇斯一样  把他们也迷倒了
You'll poison them just like you poisoned Chase.
你丈夫杀了个病人 你却要和我谈分手
Your husband killed a patient and you're breaking up with me.
是你毁了他
You ruined him.
让他是非不分
So he can't even see right from wrong.
再也意识不到生命的神圣
Can't even see the sanctity of a human life anymore.
我爱过你
I loved you.
也爱过奇斯
And I loved Chase.
看到你们这样我很心痛
I'm sorry for you both.
你们已经变成这样
For what you've become.
因为
Because...
你们再也没有退路了
There's no way back for either of you.
我在哪能领到一块
Any idea where I can get
任务完成的大牌子
A great, big "mission accomplished" banner?
恢复了理智
Got my sanity back,
执照也失而复得  现在
My license back, and now...
开玩笑吧  全回归了
You're kidding. All of them?
四个回来了三个
Three out of four.
几乎跟五个回来四个一样棒
Which is almost as good as four out of five.
那是谁
Who was the--
卡梅隆
Cameron.
难以置信
I can't believe it.
真的不敢
I mean, really. I can't...
相信
Believe it.
没错  豪斯  这很好
You were right, House. Good for you.
是啊
Yeah, it is.
她和奇斯分手了  离开了医院
She's broken up with Chase, and she's leaving the hospital.
四个留下仨  不算糟糕了
Still, three out of four ain't bad.